Guide to the Iraq Veterans Against the War Oral History Collection OH.091
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Iraq Veterans Against the War Oral History Collection
2015-2020
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Howard, Matt
OH.091
316.9 Gigabytes in 631 recordings
Iraq Veterans Against the War was founded in July 2004 by Iraq War veterans. Their membership consists of veterans and active military personnel who have served in any branch of the United States military, Reserve, or National Guard since September 11, 2001. The mission of Iraq Veterans Against the War (IVAW) is to end militarism. The organization also provides support services for returning veterans and has conducted campaigns to counter the military's narrative of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan. The Iraq Veterans Against the War Oral History Collection contains video recordings of oral history interviews with Iraq Veterans Against the War (IVAW) members conducted by staff from the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives and members of IVAW in 2015 and 2016. Topics discussed in the interview include the backgrounds of the IVAW members; the events of September 11, 2011; the post September 11 anti-war movement; the formation and internal history of IVAW; and various campaigns against United States foreign policy during the George W. Bush, Barack Obama, and Donald Trump administrations.
Scope and Contents
The Iraq Veterans Against the War Oral History Collection contains production files and video recordings of oral history interviews with Iraq Veterans Against the War (IVAW) members conducted by Michael Koncewicz of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, and Kelly Dougherty, Aaron Hughes, and Maggie Martin of IVAW in 2015 and 2016. Topics discussed in the interview include the backgrounds of the IVAW members; the events of September 11, 2011; the post September 11 anti-war movement; the formation and internal history of IVAW; and various IVAW campaigns against United States foreign policy during the George W. Bush, Barack Obama, and Donald Trump administrations. The material consists of production files in MXF format as well as MTS video files created by Tamiment staff.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by the narrator's last name.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions, with the exception of Matt Howard's and Lisa Ling's interviews, which are restricted until 2026.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Matt Howard in December 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.001.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Historical Note
Iraq Veterans Against the War was founded in July 2004 by Iraq War veterans. Their membership consists of veterans and active military personnel who have served in any branch of the United States military, Reserve, or National Guard since September 11, 2001. The mission of Iraq Veterans Against the War (IVAW) is to end militarism. The organization also provides support services for returning veterans and has conducted campaigns to counter the military's narrative of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.
Custodial History
Production files for interviews conducted in 2015 by a production company and interviews conducted in 2016 by Tamiment staff were donated by Matt Howard in 2016. These files were used to create video recordings by Tamiment staff which were stored on Digital Tamiment and Vimeo. These recordings were downloaded by Tamiment and Archival Collections Management staff in 2019 and 2020 and transferred to Research Workspace.
Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Veterans -- United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Personal narratives, American.; Oral histories (literary works); Veterans -- Political activity -- United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Protest movements -- United States.; Howard, Matt; Iraq Veterans Against the War
- Camp, Jeff, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_2)
- Copeland, Claude, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_5)
- Foster, Shawna, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_6)
- Goodwin, Nicole, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_10)
- Howard, Matt, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_3)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to this interview is restricted until 2026.
- Hughes, Aaron, 2015-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_9)
- Khalil, Ghanim, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_8)
- Ling, Lisa, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_4)
- Martin, Maggie, 2015-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_13)
- McIntosh, Brock, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_7)
- Mejía, Camilo, 2015-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_12)
- Myracle, Aaron, 2015-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_11)
- Vasquez, Jose, 2016-2020 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_91_ER_1)